wunderkit.com 2017-11-15

# Privacy Policy

We, 6Wunderkinder GmbH (hereinafter "6Wunderkinder"), regard the protection and the confidentiality of your data as very important. We collect and use your personal data in accordance with the relevant provisions of German data protection legislation. In this Privacy Policy, we would like to tell you which personal data we collect and what we use it for.

Below, 6Wunderkinder tells you about the type and extent of and the purposes for which personal data are collected and used. You can call up this information on our website anytime.

#### Controller

The controller within the meaning of German data protection laws is:

  * 6 Wunderkinder GmbH
  * Karl-Liebknecht-Straße 32
  * 10178 Berlin

If you have any questions or concerns about data protection, you are welcome to also contact us by email at this address: [support@wunderlist.com](mailto:support@wunderlist.com "support@wunderlist.com")

#### Subject of Data Protection

The subject of data protection is personal data. According to Section 3, Subsection 1 of the German Federal Data Protection Act ("Bundesdatenschutzgesetz"), these are individual details on personal or objective circumstances of a certain person or certain persons. These include details such as your name, your postal address, your email address, your telephone number or, where appropriate, even use-data.

#### Collection and Use of Data

##### Automated Data Collection

When you access 6Wunderkinder websites, your internet browser automatically transmits data for technical reasons. The following data are stored separately from other data that you may have sent us:

  * your date and time of access,
  * your browser-type and version,
  * the operating system you use,
  * the URL of the website you have previously visited,
  * the quantity of data transmitted.

For technical reasons these data are stored and are not assigned to any identifiable person at any time.

##### Data Entered by Users

You can use the Wunderlist product both with and without registering. However, you can only access Wunderlist using certain terminals such as an iPhone, iPod, iPad, Windows, Mac or Android and without additional functions. In order to make use of all its advantages, you have to register. To do this, you must enter your email address and select a password. We require these data in order to guarantee that you are able to make full use of our entire offer. We need these and possibly other data not least in order to respond to your wishes, questions and criticism.

In future, we plan to introduce an option which will allow you to design your account personally. For example, you will be able to add a photo, choose a username and set up a connection to your Facebook user account. You will not be obliged to design your account personally; this will be entirely voluntary.

The central function of Wunderlist product is task management. You will be able to use this product both online and offline.

Where Wunderlist is used solely offline, the data you enter will be stored de-centrally on your storage medium. In such a case, we will not be able to access these data.

If you use Wunderlist in combination with a registered account, all data and tasks entered will be integrated into a database. The purpose of this database is to allow you to use Wunderlist at various different levels and call up your tasks anywhere and at any time. Data are transmitted to the respective terminal using SSL encryption so that your data are transmitted securely.

We use personal data in order to enable secure, effective and user-related use of Wunderlist services, including for:

  * calling up the task-list via the internet;
  * anonymously analysing task management statistics for press releases by 6Wunderkinder and studies;
  * recommending Wunderlist by using the "Invite" function for friends and acquaintances (email address).

##### Transfer of Data

We will not transfer your data to third parties as a matter of course without letting you know in advance or asking for your prior permission. We may only transfer your data to third parties without informing you separately beforehand in the following exceptional cases as explained below:

  * If required for investigating the illegal use of Wunderlist or for legal proceedings, personal data will be transferred to the criminal investigation authorities and, if appropriate, to injured third parties. We will only do this if there are concrete indications of illegal and/or abusive behaviour. We can only transfer on your personal data if this is used to enforce General Terms and Conditions of Business or other agreements. We are also legally obliged to give certain public authorities information. These are criminal investigation authorities, public authorities which prosecute administrative offences entailing fines and the German finance authorities.
  * Occasionally we depend on contractually affiliated external companies and external service providers to supply services such as the supply of advertising measures (only if you have given your explicit prior consent), processing payments (PayPal, credit card etc.), storing your data and customer service. In such cases, information is transferred to these companies or individuals in order to enable them to process this information further. We carefully select these external service providers and review them regularly to ensure that your privacy is preserved. The service providers may only use the data for the purposes stipulated by us. We also contractually require the service providers to treat your data solely in accordance with this Privacy Policy and the German data protection laws.
  * In order to further develop our business, we may alter the corporate structure of 6Wunderkinder GmbH by changing its legal form. We may also form, sell or buy subsidiaries, divisions or parts of the company. In such transactions, customer information together with the part of the company to be transferred will be passed on. Every time personal data are transferred to third parties to the extent prescribed, 6Wunderkinder will ensure that this is done in accordance with this Privacy Policy and the relevant data protection laws.

#### Newsletter

6Wunderkinder provides a newsletter service free of charge. We use the newsletter to inform you about new products and send you general information about 6Wunderkinder. We need your email address in order to send you the newsletter. You can enter your email address on 6Wunderkinder's start page, which is available at [http://www.6wunderkinder.com](http://www.6wunderkinder.com/ "http://www.6wunderkinder.com"). We will store and use your email address solely to send you the newsletter.

Of course you can unsubscribe the newsletter at any time. Every newsletter contains the information on how you can unsubscribe the newsletter with effect for the future.

#### Cookies

6Wunderkinder stores so-called "cookies" in order to be able to offer you a comprehensive range of functions and to make it easier to use our websites. "Cookies" are small files which are stored on your computer with the help of the internet browser. If you do not want to use "cookies", you can prevent "cookies" from being stored on your computer using the corresponding settings on your internet browser. Please note that this may restrict the functional capability and the range of functions of our offer.

We use cookies and similar technologies for several purposes, including:

  * **Storing your Preferences and Settings.** Settings that enable our websites to operate correctly or that maintain your preferences over time may be stored on your device.
  * **Sign-in and Authentication.** When you sign into a website, we store a unique ID number, and the time you signed in, in an encrypted cookie on your device. This cookie allows you to move from page to page within the site without having to sign in again on each page.
  * **Security.** We use cookies to detect fraud and abuse of our websites.
  * **Analytics.** In order to provide our products, we use cookies and other identifiers to gather usage and performance data. For example, we use cookies to count the number of unique visitors to a web page or service and to develop other statistics about the operations of our products. This includes cookies from 6Wunderkinder and from third-party analytics providers.
  * **Performance.** 6Wunderkinder uses cookies for load balancing to ensure that our websites remain up and running.

In addition to the cookies 6Wunderkinder sets when you visit our websites, third parties may also set cookies when you visit Microsoft sites. In some cases, that is because we have hired the third party to provide services on our behalf, such as site analytics, support, and the collection of feedback. See, e.g., Google Analytics section below. Because your browser connects to those third parties' web servers to retrieve that content, those third parties are able to set or read their own cookies on your device and may collect information about your online activities across websites or online services.

#### Analysis of Wunderlist

##### Statistical Data

When Wunderlist is used, we collect statistical data which can be traced to you. We use it to improve Wunderlist.

##### Google Analytics

6Wunderkinder uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service of Google Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses so-called "cookies", text files which are stored on your computer and which enable you to analyse your use of Wunderlist. The information generated by the cookie on your use of Wunderlist (including your abbreviated IP address) is transmitted to a Google server in the USA and are stored there. Google will use this information to assess your use of Wunderlist, to compile reports on the activities for us and to provide more services connected with use of Wunderlist and the internet. It is also possible that Google may transmit this information to third parties if this is prescribed by law or if third parties process this information on behalf of Google.

**You can deactivate Google Analytics by means of a browser add-on if you do not want Wunderlist analysis. You can download this here:** <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de>

#### Deleting Your Data

If your data are no longer required for the aforementioned purposes, we will delete them. Completed tasks will remain stored and will be marked "Completed" in the database. If you delete your account, we will also delete all data completely from your account (lists, tasks and shared lists). Data you have entered in lists belonging to third parties will remain in existence as these are part of third party accounts. If data has to be retained for statutory reasons, these will be blocked and will then no longer be available for any further use.

#### Right to Information and Correction

You naturally have the right to receive information about the data held and stored by 6Wunderkinder about you. Equally, you have the right to have incorrect data corrected or blocked. To have this done, please contact: [support@wunderlist.com](mailto:support@wunderlist.com "support@wunderlist.com") or by post to the address given above.

#### Amendments to this Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to amend this Privacy Policy. You can call up the current version of the Privacy Policy at any time at: <http://www.6wunderkinder.com/privacy-policy>.
